# Jeremiah M. Coholich

jmcoholich@gmail.com \( \phi \) www.jeremiahcoholich.com

**Objective Statement:** New CS Masters graduate looking for an R&D position in machine learning or robotics. I am up-to-date on current machine learning literature and have three years of experience in academia implementing state-of-the-art deep learning algorithms, especially in deep reinforcement learning.

## **EDUCATION**

MS in Computer Science, Georgia Institute of Technology

Expected December 2022

Concentration: Computational Perception/Robotics

Capstone Project: Learning High-Value Footstep Placements for Quadruped Robots

GPA: 3.88 / 4.0

BS in Mechanical Engineering, The University of Texas at Austin, Highest Honors

2019

GPA: 3.98 / 4.0

## **SKILLS**

Languages Python, MATLAB, Shell scriptFrameworks PyTorch, TensorFlow, NumPy

Tools Docker, Slurm, LaTeX, Anaconda, Git, Linux, Matplotlib, Weights & Biases

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Graduate Researcher, Robot Perception and Learning Lab

June 2020 - Present

- Develop and implement novel learning-based planning and control algorithms for quadruped robots in simulation
- Reproduce results from academic papers in the field of reinforcement learning (RL) and robotics
- Create robot environments in NVIDIA IsaacGym and PyBullet simulation with procedurally-generated terrain
- Implement pipeline for reproducible training of RL policies, multi-GPU policy evaluation, and data collection
- Derive and implement vectorized analytical inverse kinematics for quadruped robot

Graduate Researcher, Laboratory for Intelligent Decision and Autonomous Robots August 2019 - May 2020

- Studied nonlinear optimization of biped walking gaits on Cassie robot from Agility Robotics
- Wrote hybrid trajectory optimization program for five-link walker on soft terrain using MATLAB, FROST, IPOPT, and Wolfram Mathematica

Undergraduate Research Assistant, Human Centered Robotics Lab

February 2018 - May 2019

- Implemented a model-based, multi-input controller with a disturbance observer and discrete-time filters for an augmentation exoskeleton under the mentorship of a PhD student
- Modeled a 3-axis robotic joint in order to aid in placement of actuators and prevent issues with gimbal lock

# **AWARDS**

- National Defense Science and Engineering Graduate (NDSEG) Fellowship, 2020
- NASA Space Technology Graduate Research Opportunities (NSTGRO) Fellowship, 2020 (declined)
- Georgia Tech President's Fellowship, 2019
- George W. Bean Endowed Presidential Scholarship, 2016 2019

## INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Associate Mechanical Engineer, SpaceX

Summer 2019

Mechanical Engineering Intern, Harmonic Bionics

Summer 2018

Mechanical Engineering Co-op, NASA Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL)

May 2017 - December 2017